<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="introduction">
        <item> The Shaykh Abu-l-\'Abbas al-Jami related to me that a certain man asked Sidi Abu-l-Hasan, “Who is your spiritual guide Sidi?” He said to him, “In the beginning it was Sidi Shaykh Abu Muhammad \'Abd as-Salam Ibn Mashish. At present I draw from ten seas, five of the sons of \'Adam and five of spiritual origin. The five Adamic are Sayyidina Muhammad and his companions, Abu Bakr, \'Umar, \'Uthman and \'Ali. The five of spiritual origin are Jibril, Mika\'il, Israfil, \'Izra\'il and ar-Ruh {the Holy Spirit}.”</item>
        <item> Thus the Way of the Shadhdhuliyyah, though traceable back through Sidi \'Abd as-Salam Ibn Mashish as well as Sidi Muhammad bin Harazim and Sidi Abu-l-Fath al-Wasiti, really has its beginning with our Shaykh, Sidi Ali Abu-l-Hasan.</item>
        <item> Sidi Ibn \'Ata \'illah reported on the authority of Sidi Shihab ad-Din Ahmad, the son of our Shaykh, that at the time of his death his father said, “I have brought to this Way {Tariqah} what no one has before me.”</item>
        <item> Thus the Way of the Shadhdhuliyyah, though it has many areas in common with the various Turuq, may Allāh be pleased with them all, is a unique Way unlike any other.</item>
        <item> The Shaykh, may Allāh preserve his secret, said, “Of all the Ways there are two: the way of travelling {suluk} and the way of attraction {jadhb}. Our Way is the Way of Jadhb. Our beginning is their end. Their beginning is our completion.” Shaykh Ibn \'Ata\' illah, whose books greatly aided in the diffusion of the teachings of our Shaykh, says in the Kitab al Hikm, “He who is illumined in the beginning is illumined in the end.” Thus the Way of the Shadhdhuliyyah is firmly based on the reality {haqiqah} that Enlightenment or Illumination {ishraq} is both in our beginning and at our end with the certain knowledge that both our beginning and end are in His Presence and by His Grace.”</item>
        <item> Shaykh Ahmad az-Zarruq, commenting on this, said, “The variety in a branch is due to the variety of its origin. The origin of Tasawwuf is in the station of \'Ihsan and it splits into two kinds: \'to worship Allāh as though you saw Him\' and \'knowing that if you do not see Him, He sees you.\' The first is the degree of the Knower; the latter is the degree of the Seeker. The Folk of ash-Shadhdhuli revolve around the first and Folk of al-Ghazali revolve around the other.”</item>
        <item> Shaykh Ibn \'Ata\'illah as-Sakandari said, “Do not think that the \'attracted\' {al-majdhub} has no path. He has a path that has been enveloped by the providential solicitude of Allāh {\' inayatu-llah} so that his way has been speedily expedited. Too often we hear that the traveller {as-salik} is more perfect than the attracted due to the traveller\'s experience of the Path and the Attracted\'s lack of experience. This is not true. He does not miss it but misses only its hardships and the length.” Thus \'attraction\' {al-jadhb} was a necessary prerequisite for the Folk {al-qawm} who took the Way of our Shaykh as the Shadhdhuli Way was par excellence that of “witnessing” {mushahadah} Allāh at the beginning of the Way which in turn fostered a great concern with \'intuition” {kashf} in contradistinction to the other ways more concerned with \'intellect\' {the rational faculty = \'aql } and not The Intellect { al-\'aql} understood as The Existentiating Reality}.</item>
        <item> Ibn \'Ata \'illah, to whom we are so indebted for our knowledge of the Way of our Shaykh, made abundantly clear that the Way of Arrival to the knowledge {al-ma\'rifah} of Allāh by insight, direct witnessing, and tasting at the beginning was the way of the elite who are the chosen of Allāh whilst the Way of Arrival to Allāh by intellection, reason and proofs was the way of the commoners who have chosen Allāh. He indicates that arrival to the knowledge of Allāh is not attained by struggle {jihad} with the self {nafs}, neither by obedience nor good deeds, for these are the product of human will {\'iradah} and humans have no will in relation to the Will of Allāh. Man cannot reach Allāh by his will alone, not by renouncing himself, humiliating himself, or destroying himself for “there is no logical nexus between the transcendent and the contingent.” Arrival to the knowledge of Allāh stems from the providential solicitude of Allāh. Real and ineffable sanctifying grace in conjunction with amorous wisdom. The \'spiritual life\' is not so much a question of choice as it is a matter of vocation and an abiding sense of having been chosen in eternity on the day of \'Alastu bi-rabbikum\'?</item>
        <item> Ibn \'Abbad ar-Rundi says, “The voyager is the one whose invocation precedes his illumination whilst the attracted is the one whose illumination precedes his invocation.”</item>
        <item> In his book Kitab at-Tanwir fi \'Isqat at-Tadabir {Light on the Cessation of Self Direction} he says, “Know that The Truth {al-haqq} has always taken the best of care for you throughout all of your life since He brought you into existence on the Day of the Decree [yawm al-muqadir}, the Day of “Am I not your Lord” and you said, “Yes, we bear witness!” Among the signs of His Care is that He caused you to know Him. He revealed Himself to you and you witnessed Him. It was He who made you speak and inspired you to affirm His Lordship [rububiyyatahu] and so confirm His Oneness.”</item>
        <item> And when your Lord took from the children of Adam, from their spines, their seed and made them to witness of their selves <br/> “Am I not your Lord ?” <br/> They said, “Yes! we bear witness.” <br/> lest you should say on the Day of Resurrection, “As for us we were not aware.” { 7:172 }</item>
        <item> This statement concerning the pre-etemal celestial witnessing is crucial to the understanding that within all human beings there is a part that always has known the Truth both of origin and destination. The whole question of the spiritual path {at-tariqah} is thus not so much a matter of going \'somewhere\' as it is an awakening to where one already is and a remembering of who one is, was and will be.</item>
        <item> The literalist objection to the Sufi doctrine of arrival {wusul} is completely misguided as it is clear that ab origine all humans had direct knowledge and direct witnessing of their Lord and, moreover, directly entered into a covenant of witness with their Lord, in the beginning and at the end. The goal of the path is, simply stated, the return to this realization by the elimination of forgetfulness.</item>
        <item> For some it is a lengthy process whereas for others, less mindless {ghaflah} perhaps, it is clearly evident by virtue of insight which is a grant or bestowal of grace from their Lord. The view of our Shaykh was that the cessation of self-direction, in itself a recognition of the necessity of a continual \'Islam {self surrender}, was the means par excellence for the cultivation of insight [kashf}, which best blooms undisturbed by agitation and the sense of \'doing\' so much evident in the contemporary world.</item>
        <item> Commenting on the saying of one of his contemporaries, “Spiritual knowledge comes from Allāh in two ways: one way, the path of the Source of generosity, and one way, the path of enormous self-exertion,” our Shaykh said, “Regarding the Source of generosity, it refers to those whom Allāh has initiated with His Divine Gift and who by this Gift have attained to obedience unto Him. Concerning the great self-exertion, this refers to those people who, by obedience unto Him, have attained to His Divine Gift.” He continued saying, “Certainty {yaqin} is a word pertaining to the apprehension of realities without a doubt and without an intervening veil. Spiritual knowledge {ma\'rifah} is a disclosure of the sciences along with the veil. When the veil is removed, we call it certainty. He who has access to the realities [haqa\'iq} is carried away in rapture {nashwata-l-tarab}. The one who has spiritual knowledge is drawn by it away from the self {nafs}. </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>


    </string-array>

    <string-array name="biographyc1">
        <item> The name of our Shaykh was \'Ali ibn \'Abd Allāh Ibn \'Abd al-Jabbar and he was of \'Alid descent of the Fatimid-Hasanid line on his father\'s side and of Fatimid-Husaynid on his mother\'s side. He was born in the small village of Ghumarah in the Rif [northern Atlas] mountains of the Maghrib in the year 593 of the Flight [1196]. The village is situated in a round valley surrounded on all sides by mountains and dominated by a large mountain rising up almost directly in the centre of the valley. This mountain, Jabal \'Alam, [Flag Mountain], was to play a very significant part in the life of our Shaykh. Ghumarah, near the base of the mountain, was a stronghold of orthodox Islam in a sea of heterodox Berber clans much devoted to magic, in which the shurafā were traditionally the propagators and guarantors of orthopractic Islam as well as, by dint of being of the Idrisid line, the local aristocracy in the true sense of the meaning of that word. </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc2">
        <item> Little is known about his very early life, though, as a member of the shurafā [ahlul-bayt] we can extrapolate that from a very early age he was tutored intensively first by his mother and then by his father and the local \'ulamā in all aspects of the Din. The deep dedication and devotion to Islam that prevails among the great majority of the shurafā {especially those untouched by connection to positions of worldly rule} is a well known phenomenon which prevails to the present day all across the Muslim world. </item>
        <item> It seems likely that our Shaykh was sent to Fas {Fez} founded by Maulay Idris Ibn \'Abdullah, a great-grandson of Sayyiduna al-Hasan, which was the city par excellence in the Maghrib for Islamic education as it was the home of the great madrassah of Qarrawiyyin. Here he began his formal religious training and it is presumed that is was in Fas that he first studied with and entered the Way of Tasawwuf at the hand of his first Shaykh, Sidi \'Abd Allāh Ibn Harazim. </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc3">
        <item> It was also in Fas that his heart was first moved to find and contact the Qutb of the Age. This movement of the heart finally led him to make his first great journey to the East, travelling some 3000 miles which at that time, by ship and camel caravan, took nine months to a year. No records exist of those he contacted on his way but we must assume that, given the nature of his search, he came into contact with a great number of the Friends of Allāh on this journey.  </item>
        <item> Finally in al-Iraq, according to the biographer Ibn Sabbagh, he came into contact with the great Shaykh Abul Fath al Wasiti, the direct successor of Shaykh Abul \'Abbās Ahmad ar-Rifā\'i, may Allāh be merciful to them both and sanctify their secret, the founder {Al-Mu\'assis} of the Rifā\'i Tariqah. Undoubtedly he came to know of Shaykh Abul Fath al Wasiti in Baghdad, which at the time was the great centre of the Muslim world, and then tracked the Shaykh to the marshlands in the south of al-Iraq at the mother Zawiya in Bata\'ih, between Basra and Wasit. Here, after taking the hand of Shaykh Abu Fath, of whom he said, “There was nobody in all of al-Iraq like him,” and upon inquiring of him concerning the Qutb, he was told to return to his own home in the West where he would find the Qutb living on the top of a mountain in the middle of a valley surrounded by mountains; precisely, as is so often the case, from whence he first set out. </item>
        <item> After journeying for another year, during which most who have studied his life are inclined to believe that he made his first Hajj to the Ancient House in Makkah al-Mukarramah and ziyyārah to the resting place of the Prophet, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him, in al-Madinah al-Munawwarah, he returned to his home in Ghumarah in the valley of Jabal \'Alam. Later in his life he referred to the whole period beginning with his contact with Shaykh Ibn Harazim till his return to the valley of Jabal \'Alam as, “the beginning of my cause {ibtidā\'u amri}.” </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc4">
        <item> Making enquiries he was informed that, indeed, at the top of the mountain situated on a plateau-like ridge was the retreat {ribitah} of a highly pious and deeply spiritual ascetic, who, after a full and long life in the valley, had moved to the top of the mountain to devote himself, in his later years, to Allāh. He was of the tribe of Beni \'Arus, a descendant of Maulay Idris in the Hasanid line. His name was \'Abd as-Salām Ibn Mashish Ibn Abi Bakr, may Allāh be merciful to him and sanctify his secret.  </item>
        <item> Shaykh \'Abd as-Salām took from two teachers, Shaykh \'Abd ar-Rahman al-Madani az-Zayyat, of whom little is known, and Shaykhul Mashayikh, Abu madyan Shu\'ayb ibn al-Husayn, termed al-Ghawth, may Allāh have mercy on them and sanctify their secret, from whom sprang many great Shuyukh. Shaykh Abu Madyan al Ghawth was born in Ishbiliyyah {Seville}, studied in Fas from which, upon completing his studies he travelled, according to some, to Makkah for Hajj, where he met the Qutb, \'Abdul Qadir Jilani, Allāh preserve his secret, and finally returned to settle and teach in Bijayah {Bougie}, in Tunis. His spiritual sons and grandsons are numerous, may Allāh have mercy on them and include Shaykh al-Jazuli, Shaykh Yusuf Abu Hajjaj and Shaykh Ibn \'Arabi\'s murid, ash-Shushtarti. </item>
        <item> The outlook of Shaykh \'Abd as-Salām Ibn Mashish was deeply rooted in the Shari\'ah and Ibn Sabbagh reports that upon being asked to prescribe a spiritual practice to a seeker he replied, “Am I a prophet? The most obligatory of duties is the observance of the essential commands and abstention from what is deemed wrong; continue what is obligatory and refrain from what is prohibited while securing your heart from worldly desires, inclinations and ambition. Accept with contentment {rida} what has been allotted to you by Allāh”. He was known for his almost total disdain of worldly possessions and secular authority. He taught that trust in Allāh {Tawakkul \'alallāh} was the summit of true worship {\'ibadah} and an ascetic {zuhd} life its proof. Fear {khawf} of Allāh is protection from evil. Love {mahabbah} is the pole around which revolves all good {khayr}. Faith {Iman} which is security based on revelation {wahy} is the way to witnessing {mushāhadah}. Only by drowning in the source of the Ocean of Oneness {\'aynu bahril wahdah} can one hope to transcend one\'s own contingent attributes in favour of absorption in the Eternal attributes.  </item>
        <item> His most immediate legacy is the Tasliyyah {prayer on the Prophet} that he composed {included in this volume} popularly known as as–Salat al-Mashishiyyah, which is a summary of the doctrine of Sayyidina Muhammad, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him, as the Universal Man {al-insānul kāmil}, both ground and unified secret {sirr al-jami\'}, as well as the supreme veil {al-hijab al-adham} of the entire cosmos as it emerges from the essence {dhāt} to the world of infinite eternal possibility {jabarūt} to the world of the Essence reflected in Attribute {malakūt} to the world of the reflection of the Attributes {mulk}. A redaction of the tasliyyah, al-wadhifah ash-Shādhiliyyah, is recited until this day by many branches of the Shādhiliyya especially in the Maghrib. His kunya is qindil al-jabal {lamp of the mountain} and from his maqām {burial spot} atop the Jabal \'Alam an enormous many-branched oak tree has grown shading an outdoor masjid: a \'picture\' in this world of his station in the spiritual realms. </item>
        <item> The entire story of the meeting of Shaykh \'Ali Abul Hasan and the Qutb, Shaykh al-Mashish, is given in the first section of Volume Two. In short, after an initial rejection in which Shaykh al-Mashish instructed him to further purify himself, which he did by immersing himself in a spring at the base of the mountain, he made a second ascent of the mountain and this time the Qutb met him just short of the top and, after reciting Abul Hasan\'s full genealogy, embraced him with great love, accepted him utterly and completely, and, in the course of their time together, transmitted to our Shaykh all that he had sought on his journey. The Qutb fully opened {futūh} him to the spiritual life and confirmed him in the walāyah {spiritual office}. In the fullness of time Shaykh al-Mashish directed him to proceed to \'Ifriqiyah {part of modern day Tunisia} and to settle in a village called Shādhilah. The Shaykh told him that after a time he would receive an inspiration {ilhām} from Allāh which would be his signal to proceed to the city of Tunis where he would be opposed. He should, however, remain there until a certain event would occur which would allow him to end his stay in Tunis. From there he should proceed to the East where, he was informed, “you will become the Qutb”. </item>
        <item> On departing from his Shaykh he asked his advice. Sidi Ibn Mashish replied, “Oh \'Ali, Allāh is Allāh and people are people. The remembrance of Allāh will live in your heart. Refrain from dependence on people and keep your heart from inclining to them. Carry on with your duties. The guidance of Allāh will be always with you. Do not refer to people except that Allāh commands you. Your sovereignty {wilayah} has been perfected by Allāh. Say, “Allāh I ask Your Mercy that I may not incline to or yearn for people. Keep me from their evil and enrich me by not seeking help from them. Single me out from them for You are capable of all things.” </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc5">
        <item> Thus did he set out for Shādhilah, a small village mid-way between Qayrawan and Tunis, which in later life he would call mabda\'u dhuhūri {the place where my light became evident}. Rather than taking a dwelling in the village itself he sought shelter in a cave on Jabal Zaghwan where, in the company of Sidi \'Abd Allāh Ibn Salamah al-Habibi who is described as being of ahli kashf {the people of insight}, he entered into a long period of retreat. He did this because he had not yet received permission {\'idhn} to guide others and he wished to complete the process of his inner discipline by which he sought to overcome the effects stemming from the residue of human bias.  </item>
        <item> Upon his arrival he had found that he was somehow expected in Shādhilah and that a number of people had gathered to meet him tough no mention of his coming had been circulated. Knowing his own station he wished to remove himself as far as possible from people until the two above items had been realized. The steepness of the path and difficulty of access afforded by the cave on Jabal Zaghwan were entirely consonant with making sure that only very dedicated and determined people would be able to reach him. </item>
        <item> Life on the mountain was extremely rigorous both in terms of his spiritual and physical practice. During this time he subsisted almost entirely on mountain herbs and water from a nearby spring. The constant refrain of those days was flight {hijrah} to Allāh through emptying, effacement and disappearance. His spiritual practice at this time consisted of extended periods of fasting known as siyām Dāwūd {the fast of Prophet David, peace be upon him} and intense jihad {struggle} with the nafs {self} through the agencies of worship and devotion. In later years many marvellous stories were told by his companion Sidi al-Habibi of events that took place on Jabal Zaghwan; all are fully related in Volume Two. </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc6">
        <item> It was during this period when he received his nisbah {provenance} “ash-Shādhili”. Most people believe it stems from his period of dwelling near the village of Shādhilah but the real story is quite different. It came about in the form of ru\'ya {vision of veridical dream} in which he asked why he should be styled ash-Shādhili when he was not from Shādhilah and in response he heard Allāh speak to him, saying. “Oh \'Ali! You are ash-Shādhili with tashdīd on the dhal, meaning, \'I have set you apart for Me\'.” </item>
        <item> Shortly after this he had a further ru\'ya in which he at last received both his \'idhn and his orders {\'amr billāh}. He says, “I was told, \'Ali go down to the people. They will benefit from you.\' I replied, \'Oh my Lord and Sustainer relieve me from their company.\' I was told, \'Go down \'Ali. Peace will be with you.\' I said, \'Will you leave me to the people to eat from their money?\' I was told, \'Spend as you like oh \'Ali. I am your financier. Spend as you like from your own pocket or from the unseen {\'inshi\'ta min al-jayb aw \'inshi\'ta min al-ghayb}.\'” </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc7">
        <item> Thus it was sometime between the years 638 and 642 of the Flight {1240-1244}, when our Shaykh was in his late 40\'s, that he entered Tunis, settled in a house near Masjid al-Balat {the Tiled or Court Mosque}, and began calling {da\'wah} the people {al-qawm} to Allāh. In those days Tunis was under the rule of the Hafsid Sultan, Abu Zakkariyyah. </item>
        <item> Our Shaykh knew Tunis, having visited the city before, on his first journey to the East. He told an interesting story of an event that took place that time. “When I entered the city Tunis, as a young man, I found there a great famine and I came upon starving people in the market places. I said to myself, \'Had I the money to buy bread for these hungry people I would surely do it.\' Then there came a thought to my innermost heart, \'Take what is in your pocket.\' So I shook my pocket and, lo, in it there were silver coins.  So I went to the baker at Bab al-Minārah and said to him, \'Count up your bread.\' He counted it for me. Then I offered it to the people who seized upon it. I drew out the coins and handed them to the baker. He took them to be counterfeit, saying, \'These are Maghribi and you Maghribah are alchemists.\' So I gave him by burnous and a small bag as pawn on the price of the bread and turned to the door. Right by the door stood a man who said to me, \'Oh \'Ali, where are the coins?\' I gave them to him and he took them in his hand and then returned them saying, \'Pay the baker.\' I paid the baker who accepted them from me saying, \'these are good.\' I took my burnous and bag and searched for the man but I did not find him.“ </item>
        <item> “I remained for some days confused within myself until on Friday I went to Jami\' az-Zaytūnah, close by the reserved section on the east side of the masjid. Then if offered rak\'atayn {tahiyyatul masjid} and as I pronounced peace upon the two angels, lo, I found the man seated on my right. I greeted him and he smiled at me, saying, \'Oh \'Ali! You thought to yourself, \'Had I the money to buy bread for these hungry people I would surely do it.\' You would be as generous as Allāh, The Generous, toward His creatures. Had He willed, He would have fed them for He is more aware of their need than you.\' I asked, \'Oh Sidi, by Allāh, who are you?\' He replied, \'I am Ahmad al-Khidr {the Green Man}. I was in China and I was told, \'Go and look for my Friend \'Ali in Tunis.\' And I came hurrying to you.\' After I completed Salatul Jum\'ah {Friday Prayers} I looked for him but I did not find him.” </item>
        <item> The young man who had first visited Tunis on his way to the East seeking the Qutb only to be instructed to return to the West to find him, which he, in reality, did, had now returned again to Tunis as a very changed man. He had found what he sought and in turn was on his way to becoming that which he sought and Tunis was prepared to receive him and his call to the Way of Allāh and His Messenger, blessings and peace be upon him. </item>
        <item> His home, a cell in a subterranean chamber, al-Magharah ash-Shādhuliyya, soon became the centre for his students and his disciples {muridūn} who were known as “al-awliya al-arba’un” {the forty friends} and included a great diversity of excellent men endowed with spiritual gifts and blessings, from all walks of life and from many different regions. Many people came to him in that time for inspiration and guidance and word spread of his purity and state of spiritual elevation. </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc8">
        <item> As so often happens, and as was foretold, this provoked envy {hasad} especially in the heart of one man, Abul Qasim Ibn al Bara, a faqih {canon lawyer}, and, according to Ibn Sabbagh and Ibn Iyad, the Qadi {religious judge} of Tunis, though records of the time do not note his name among the holders of that office. What is likely is that he was either a neighbourhood faqih or a district ‘alim or a Qadi and not necessarily the chief Qadi. Perhaps he as the vociferous khatib of a large congregational {jum’ah} masjid who had studied fiqh or he may even have been simply an influential merchant who, having read a number of books, considered himself the local arbiter of what is and what is not Islam, a type known then as a ‘shop-keeper faqih’ and today as an ‘engineer faqih’. Exactly what office he did or did not hold is, in truth, irrelevant. He was, and his ‘type’ continues to be virulent in our own time, a man suffering from the common disease, ‘rabies theologica’ whose symptoms are envy, hatred, bigotry, vindictiveness and, above all, ignorance.</item>
        <item> His first attempt to bring harm to our Shaykh was an endeavour to bring legal charges against him but he was unable to do so. His next attempt was to get the ear of the Sultan and seek to paint a picture of our Shaykh as first an impostor with claims of being a Sharif and a Shaykh and a Fatimi and, secondly, of greater interest to the Sultan, as an agitator who was inciting the people against the throne.</item>
        <item> The last charge immediately provoked the attention of the Sultan. For although, in general, the Hafsid dynasty was a tolerant one, it is the nature of rulers to be fearful for their thrones and the continuation of their rule. A group of ‘ulamā and fuqahā were gathered in the palace whilst the Sultan was seated behind a screen. They began questioning our Shaykh and questioned at first his genealogy specifically in regard to his claim to be a Sharif. He was able to respond easily to these questions by giving his full nasab of provenance which clarified the legitimacy of his claims and established his precise connection to ahlul bayt, may Allāh protect it. They then moved on to a discussion of the sciences, questioning him first in the realm of revealed science {al-‘ilmul mawhubah} and then in the realm of the acquired sciences {al-ulumul maktasibah}. In the first realm they were unable to answer as he released upon them a flood of knowledge which silenced them and the second realm was discussed with great equity in the manner of colleagues. It was clear that none of the charges made by Ibn al-Bara were of any consequence and the Sultan summoned Ibn Bara to him and said, “This man is one of the greatest saints and you have no power over him.” Ibn Bara replied, “By Allāh, if he should leave this palace he will bring the people of Tunis in upon you and they would throw you from your throne. Even now they are gathered at your door,” for indeed many of the muridūn were waiting outside the palace anxious to know of the outcome of his meeting with the ‘ulamā and fuqahā, and not least, the Sultan.</item>
        <item> All of those that had been gathered for the questioning, including Ibn Bara, were dismissed by the Sultan save the Shaykh who asked only for a jug of water, a carpet and a word with one of his muridūn who had been waiting without. He informed the murid that, he would be absent from the muridūn only for the day and that he would, ‘inshaAllāh, offer the evening Salah in their company. To the Sultan he said, “By Allāh, were I not trained to act in accord with the law I would surely walk out here or there,” pointing to first one wall, then another, which opened as he pointed at them. Whereupon he began to make his ablution {wudu} preparatory to offering his Salāh and the Sultan took leave of him.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc9">
        <item> When our Shaykh had finished his salāh and bestowed greetings upon the two angels he began to offer up his supplications {ad-du\'ā} and was very inclined to ask the wrath of Allāh on the Sultān and Ibn Bara when he heard the following words, “Truly Allāh will not be pleased with you if you make supplication with anger toward a fellow creature,” which caused him to offer the following du\'ā which became many years later part of his Ahzāb: “Oh You whose throne is wider than the heaven and the earth, the preservation of which is no burden, the Most-Sublime, The All-Mighty {2:256} I ask you for faith in Your care, a faith by which my heart will remain undisturbed from anxiety for sustenance and fear of creatures. Draw me near to You in a way that tears the veils as You did with\'Ibrahim, Your Friend and Messenger, who spoke to You and thereby did not need the help of Your Angel Jibril. He did not even need to ask You. You kept him safe from the fire of his enemy. How can anyone be in need of a veil to shroud him from the harm of his enemies when You have made him not to be in need of the help of Friends. I pray that You will conceal me in Your Nearness until I cannot see or feel the nearness or farness of any other thing.\'You have the Power over all things.\'”{2:19}</item>
        <item> When he had completed his du\'ā he lay on his side and napped as is the custom {sunnah} in the afternoon. In that afternoon, a favourite slave girl of the Sultan suddenly felt a great pain and immediately died. In the consternation which followed, as her body was being removed in preparation for washing and shrouding her, a censer in the room was tipped over. Suddenly fire spread in the straw mats and carpets and ran to the bedclothes until the personal quarters of the Sultān were all in flame.</item>
        <item> On the outskirts of Tunis, amongst the gardens, lived the brother of the Sultān, Abu,\'Abd Allāh al-Lihyāni. When, from his garden, he saw smoke over the city he sent to find the cause. Upon being told that the palace was in flames he had his horse saddled and rushed straight away to the palace. There he found his brother, the Sultān, in great grief and trepidation. Grief on the account of the loss of one of his beloveds and the loss of his quarters and trepidation over his arrest of our Shaykh. In his mind the two things had become connected through the Qadr of Allāh, He now knew full well the meaning of the āyāt: “Truly We have created all things according to destiny {44:49}</item>
        <item> The brother of the Sultān, Abu\'Abd Allāh al-Lihyāni, was a frequent visitor of our Shaykh and when he had heard the whole story he said to his brother, “What is this situation into which Ibn Bara has dragged you? He has caused you to fall, by Allāh, into ruin, you and those with you.” whereupon he went in to our Shaykh who was still in detention in the public part of the palace. He said to him “Ya Sidi, my brother is without knowledge of your spiritual reality. It was not his fault but that of Ibn Bara, who got him into this.” Our Shaykh replied, “By Allāh! Your brother does not possess authority over good or evil, death or life, or the raising of the dead in respect to himself. How then does he possess authority over them with respect to others?”</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc10">
        <item> Abu\'Abd Allāh al-Lihyāni, in the company of our Shaykh, departed the palace and they arrived at the Masjid Balat in time to offer the evening Sālāh in the company of the muridun. After some few days the Shaykh disposed of his quarters and informed the muridun that in accord with their plans they would shortly all be departed to the East for Hajj. Just prior to their departure he met Ibn Bara and said to him, “You see. I am making room for you in Tunis.”</item>
        <item> As they departed Tunis, a messenger was sent from the Sultān, who, much troubled at the Shaykh\'s departure, begged him to return. He said, “I am not leaving except with the intention of Hajj if Allāh, may He be exalted, wills. But when Allāh will have fulfilled my intention, I shall, inshaAllāh return.” </item>
        <item> Upon arriving in al-Iskandariyyah they were greeted with some residue of the days in Tunis. Ibn Bara, in the manner of such people, had sent a written message by fast courier to the Sultān of Misr {Egypt}, warning him of our Shaykh and stating, “This man who is coming to you has stirred up in our country and will do likewise in your land.” This caused the Sultān to order our Shaykh to be detained in the barracks of the military camp in al-Iskandariyyah.</item>
        <item> During this internment in the military barrack a delegation of chiefs of some surrounding tribes {al-Qaba\'il} heard of our Shaykh and came to visit to ask his du\'ā for relief from a heavy tax which had been levied upon them by the Sultān. He told them, “InshaAllāh, tomorrow we shall depart for al-Qahirah {Cairo} and there we shall discuss your case with the Sultān.” The next day the Shaykh, in the company of many muridun, departed via the Gate of the Lotus Tree for al-Qāhirah. Even though the guards were manning the gates no one spoke to them or saw them. They arrived at the Citadel where the Shaykh requested an audience with the Sultān {Sultān as-Sālik, the last of the Ayyubids} who was greatly perplexed, saying, “How is this? We have ordered you to be held in al-Iskandariyyah. What have you to say for yourself, oh Shaykh?” Our Shaykh replied that he had come on behalf of the Qaba\'il whereupon the Sultān, in anger, said, “Intercede for yourself. Look you here at this attestation sworn out against you in Tunis by Ibn Bara and signed by his hand.” Our Shaykh replied, “Oh Sultān, you and I and the Qaba\'il are in the hand of Allāh.” The Shaykh then rose to leave. The Sultān sat motionless and speechless and his courtiers, much surprised that he had not demurred at such behaviour, went to him only to find that he had become paralysed. They ran after our Shaykh begging him to return. He did and approached the Sultān and gently shook him. The Sultān returned to himself and, having realised his error, asked for the pardon of our Shaykh and his du\'ā. He wrote in his own hand to the governor in al-Iskandariyyah instructing him to remove the taxes on the Qaba\'il and restore what had been taken from them.</item>
        <item> Our Shaykh, after a few more days as the guest of the Sultān in the Citadel, left in the company of the muridun, completed the Hajj and returned once again to Tunis.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc11">
        <item> Upon his return he dwelt in a house within Bāb al-Jadid in a ravine called ash-Sha\'riyah. He remained there a long time until one day there arrived the future Shaykh and Wali, Abul\'Abbās, al-Mursi. When the Shaykh looked him in the face he said, “Truly no one has brought me back to Tunis except this young man.” This was so because in a ru\'yā he had seen that there would come to him a young man from al-Andalus who would be his khalifah {successor} and that it would be in Tunis that this man would come to pass. The full story of this is in the second book of Volume II but, in short, this young man was Sidi, Abul Abbās al-Mursi who, ten years earlier in Mursiah had a ru\'ya in which he had met a man clad in green atop a mountain whom he recognized as the Khalifatu-z-Zamān. After ten years which included his studies in Mursiah, meetings with the Friends in al-Andalus, departure for Hajj, shipwreck and the loss of his parents at sea, separation from his own brother, being castaway on the coast of North Africa, and becoming a caretaker of a small masjid on the outskirts of Tunis, he, at last, met his and our Shaykh. They both, in the manner of such meetings between the Friends of Allāh, instantly recognized one another and they remained together first as Shaykh and Murid, and later as father-in-law and son-in-law. After the death of our Shaykh, it was Sidi Shaykh Abul Abbās al-Mursi, as his Khalifah, who became our Shaykh and so continued the way.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc12">
        <item> All of that is to get a bit ahead of this introduction to our Shaykh but it was this meeting, so long looked forward to by both of them, that precipitated the move to al-Iskandariyyah which was to be his final home and the centre from which the Way would radiate out into the world after his death. The confirmation of this came, typically, in a ru\'yā in which, as he related, “I saw the Prophet, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him, in a dream and he said to me,\'Ya\'Ali go to Misr and again raise up forty sincere ones {siddiqun}.\' It was the season of summer and intense heat so I said,\'Ya Sidi Rasul Allāh, the heat is intense.\' and he said to me,\'Lo the clouds will give you shadow,\' and I said,\'I fear thirst,\' and he replied,\'Lo, the sky will rain for you every day,\' and he promised me seventy miraculous gifts {karāmah} on my journey.” After this ru\'ya he instructed the muridun to prepare to depart for the land of Misr.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc13">
        <item> Many amazing things took place on this journey, but one is of great significance and, though I wish to just briefly introduce the reader to our Shaykh, it must be told, for by knowing it, many things will be put into perspective.</item>
        <item> This story was related to the father of Ibn Sabbagh, the author of “The Pearl of Secrets and the Gem of Devoted Ones” {Durat al-\'Asrār wa Tuhfat al-Abrār}, by the Shaykh and reader of Qur\'an, Abu\'Abd Allāh an-Nāsikh, and it is about the great Shaykh and Wali, Abu\'Ali Ibn as-Sammat, who accompanied our Shaykh on the journey. In the interest of brevity I will summarize most of it but at the end I will tell you exactly what was said.</item>
        <item> When they set out it seemed that our Shaykh preferred the interior road and Shaykh Yunus Abu\'Ali preferred the coastal road. Since they were both great shuyukh and awliyā\' it was not a matter of any disagreement as Allāh would not have put one over the other. So they went their separate ways and later came together in the road just before it enters al-Iskandariyyah. After the Sālāh, of the Dawn, Shaykh Abu\'Ali went to the tent of the Shaykh and, upon entering it, behaved in a most uncustomary way, conversing in a speech no one understood. When he was taking leave of the Shaykh he said, “Yā Sidi, extend your hand that I may kiss it,” and departed in tears. Everyone was very amazed at this because heretofore they had been equals and treated one another as such. Here I pick up the account of Sidi an-Nāsikh.</item>
        <item> “When he had gone a little way he turned to the companions and said,\'Last night I saw the Prophet of Allāh, blessings and peace be upon him, who said to me,\'Yā Yunus! Yusuf Abul Hajjāj al-Uqsuri {the successor of Shaykh\'Abd ar-Razzaq al-Jazuli who took the way from the Ghawth, Shaykh Abul Madyan, may Allāh have mercy upon them and preserve their secret} was in Misr and he was the Qutb of his time. Last night he died and Allāh caused him to be succeeded by Abul Hasan Ash-Shādhili.\' So I went to him as one possessing the station {maqam} of the Qutb.\' When we reached al-Iskandariyyah and the people came out to meet us, I saw Shaykh Abu\'Ali strike with his hands his saddle saying with tears streaming from his eyes,\'Oh people of this land, if you knew who it is who is advancing toward you in this caravan you would surely kiss the feet of his camel, which, by Allāh, have carried to you a great blessing.\'”</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc14">
        <item> So it was that in the year 646 {1246} at the age of 50 our Shaykh, now confirmed as the Qutb of his time, in the company of his muridun entered the city of al-Iskandariyyah. Many people came out to greet him and a great feeling of love and acceptance was felt throughout the city. It seemed even that the sea itself welcomed him as it was in one of those states that occur in the summer when not a wave comes ashore and the Great Middle Sea appears like a vast lake stretching forth forever and forever to the edge where the sea and the sky meet, mingle, merge and there is no barrier between heaven and earth. Upon entering the city he remarked. “When I drew near to the land of Misr I was told,\'Oh\'Ali, the days of trial {mihan} are past and the days of blessing {minan} have come. The difficult has been followed by ease, following the example of your forefather.\'”</item>
        <item> “For truly with difficulty comes ease, truly with difficulty comes ease {94:5-6}</item>
        <item> He settled in one of the towers facing the sea which had been bequeathed to him by the Sultān. The bottom of the building was for the animals, the middle was for the fuqarā and contained a large masjid, and our Shaykh dwelt in the upper rooms where he was married and his children were born. The people came and his Way spread throughout the world.</item>
        <item> We must close the curtain on those years in al-Iskandariyyah else the introduction to the life of our Shaykh would consume a forest. By the infinite Grace of Allāh he was blessed with muridun who treasured his words and sought to live by them. Though he wrote no books, saying when questioned on this matter, “My companions are my books.” he was given a great ability of discourse. His greatest capacity, a product of his station, was that of totally emptying himself of his\'self\' and speaking from a place of pure inspiration which in turn deeply inspired his listeners. </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc15">
        <item> One of his muridun, the faqih, Shaykh\'Izz ad-Din Ibn\'Abd as-Salām, said, regarding the discourse of our Shaykh, “Listen to these words from the unseen, newly sprung from Allāh.”</item>
        <item> “The full cup is spiritual knowledge {ma\'rifah} of The Truth {al-haqq} which is imparted from that clean, pure and clear drink to whomsoever He desires of His chosen slaves from among the creation. At times the drinker sees this cup as material form {surah}; at times he sees it as meaning {ma\'nawiyah}; at times he sees it as knowledge {\'ilmiyyah}. Form is the portion of bodies and selves {anfus}; the meaning is the portion of the hearts and intellects; the knowledge is the portion of the spirits {arwah} and the secret selves {asrār}.</item>
        <item> “Oh what a drink; how sweet it is! The blessing of Allāh is upon whoever drinks it continually without ceasing and we petition Allāh for His bounty.\'Such is the bounty of Allāh that He gives it to whom He Wills for Allāh is the possessor of great bounty.\' {62:4}</item>
        <item> “Sometimes a company of lovers will assemble and they are given to drink from one cup or it may be that they are given to drink from many cups. Sometimes one person is given to drink from one cup and more than one cup. It may be that the drinks will vary according to the number of cups. Or it may be that the drinking from any one cup will vary even though a great number of friends drink from the same cup.”</item>
        <item> He was again questioned about love and he said, “Love is something granted by Allāh to the heart of His Slave which distracts him from everything else other than Him. To the point that you see your lower self inclining to Him, the intellect protecting itself by spiritual knowledge of Him, the spirit rapt in His Presence, the inner secret soul overwhelmed in contemplation of Him. The slave asks for more, and more is given, and he enters into the sweetest of delights of spiritual communion with Him. He is clad in raiment that befits the approach to Him upon the carpet of proximity and he comes into contact with virgin reality and revealed science. For that reason it is said that the awliyā are the brides of Allāh.”</item>
        <item> The one who questioned said to the Shaykh, “Now that I have come to know of love tell me, what is the drink {sharāb} of love, what is the cup {kā\'s} of love, who is the cup bearer {sāqi}, what is the tasting {dhawq}, what is the drinking {shurb}, what is repletion {riy}, what is intoxication {sukr} and what is sobriety {sahw}?”</item>
        <item> He replied, may Allāh sanctify his secret, “The drink is the light radiating from the beauty of the Beloved. The cup is the distillation of the subtle essence of the Mercy {lutf} which brings that light into contact with the lips of the heart. The Cup bearer is He who befriends the greatest of the elect and the righteous ones from among His slaves. He is Allāh, the One who knows the capacities and affairs of His Friends. If to anyone there is disclosed that beauty, if he enjoys it for one breath or two, and then the veil is dropped over it, he is the yearning\'taster\'. If he continues for an hour or more he is the\'drinker\'. If the experience becomes continuous and the drink lasts until his veins and all his members become filled with the treasured lights of Allāh then that is repletion. Often one becomes unconscious of sense and mental perceptions so that he knows neither what is said nor what he said, that is intoxication. Sometimes the cups circulate among them, states differ, they are turned back to Remembrance {dhikr} mystical states {ahwāl} and the statutory injunctions {furud}. They are not veiled from the physical attributes in spite of their having drunk as much as they could. That is the time of their sobriety, of the broadening of their mental vision and of the increase of their works. So by the stars of knowledge and the moon of unity they are guided across the night and by the sun of spiritual knowledge they obtain light.\'These are the party of Allāh...and lo, is it not the partisans of Allāh who are the victorious?\'” {58:22}</item>
        <item> “In Qayrawān I was ill and I saw in a dream the Prophet, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him. He said,\'Cleanse your robes of all filth and you will enjoy the help of Allāh with every breath.\' I asked,\'What are my robes, Oh Rasul Allāh?\' He replied,\'Allāh has clothed you with the robe of spiritual knowledge {ma\'rifah}, with the robe of love {mahabbah}, with the robe of unity {tawhid}, with the robe of faith {iman}, and with the robe of submission {islam}. If anyone has spiritual knowledge, everything becomes of little account; if anyone loves Allāh all things become easy; if anyone asserts the unity of Allāh, nothing is associated with him; if anyone has faith {āmana} in Allāh then he is safe {amina} from every thing; if anyone is resigned to Allāh rarely does he disobey Him and if he does he returns repentant asking to be excused and finding his excuse accepted.\' As he spoke, blessings and peace be upon him, I knew the meaning of the saying of Allāh,\'Your robe, cleanse it!\'”{74:4}</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc16">
        <item> People of every level attended his talks and he travelled widely throughout the land of Misr calling the people to Allāh and inspiring them anew with the message of Realization, Liberations and Truth. Ibn\'Iyyad in al-\'Aliyyah writes, “When the Shaykh, may Allāh be content with him, came into the land of Misr from al-Maghrib, he started calling people to Allāh the Exalted. All kinds of people responded to that call. Among his gatherings {majālis} was Sidi Shaykh\'Izz ad-Din Ibn\'Abd as-Salām, Shaykh Daqiq al-\'Id, Shaykh al-Mudhiri Ibn Salāh, Shaykh Asfur, and Shaykh Ibn\'Awf, Allāh preserve their secret. These were the most renowned scholars {\'ulamā} of their time in the East and the West. Also among them were Shaykh Ibn Surāqah and the\'Ālim Yā Sin, a student of Ibn\'Arabi, may Allāh be content with him. They used to attend his discourse in al-Madrassah al-Kāmilah in al-Qāhirah with great respect as students of the Shaykh. Shaykh Badr ad-Din, the great\'ālim and Chief Qādi, who was a wali and the son of a wali and the grandson of a wali used to say that he was living in the barakah of Shaykh Abul- Hasan. He was proud to be among his muridun and was proud to attend his funeral in Humaythira.”</item>
        <item> Not only did he speak to people of every level of understanding but also people of varying degrees of sympathy. At one of those gatherings, in response to a listener who sought to be deliberately provocative by asking a question about the subject of\'The Spirit {ar-Ruh}\' which Allāh has, seemingly, placed out of bounds of understanding, he gave the following answer: “\'And they question you concerning The Spirit. Say, The Spirit is at the command of my Lord. You have been given of knowledge nothing except a little.\' {17:87} Now what indication have you there from of the ignorance of the sincere friends and of the illustrious favourites of Allāh?</item>
        <item> “The disclosure is that a question occurs by means of four particles: with hāl {is it this or that?}, with kayfa {how?}, with limā {why?} and with man {who?}. With hāl occurs the question as to whether a thing exists or not? With kayfa occurs the question concerning the state of a thing. With limā occurs the question in regards to the cause of the thing and with man occurs the question as to the source of a thing. There is nothing of the aforementioned in the āyah. If you say,\'In it is the meaning of {is it this or that}\' requiring the question,\'Is the Spirit existent or non-existent?\' then surely they acknowledged beforehand its existence, for, if this were not so, He {Allāh} would not have said,\'And they question you concerning The Spirit\'. So it is established that they acknowledge its existence and thus this argument is rendered of no account.</item>
        <item> “And it contains no question regarding the state {kayfa}, how is it? And no question regarding the cause {limā}, why this and why that? If their question referred to these two they would not have been contented with His Answer,\'Say The Spirit is at the command of my Lord.\' and they would have made a disturbance and wrapped themselves in their robes to depart since that was their practice, way and desire. So it is established that the question refers only to the object itself,\'From who {man} is it?\' By the evidence of the reply and clear and conclusive explanation of His Statement:\'Say The Spirit is at the command of my Lord.\' Since the Messenger, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him, knew what they asked, he answered for Allāh with those words as you say,\'We ask you about Ādam?\' and the one questioned understands the request and says\'Ādam is of clay.\' Then if he is satisfied with the reply he is contented and the opponent does not go back except with a great understanding from the Truth which has no refutal.</item>
        <item> “So how does a claimant assert that He is not known and that it is not fitting that He be known? For surely Allāh has caused spiritual knowledge of Himself to be binding upon us, even though He has no likeness. And if we were to squander it, surely we would be disbelievers or disobedient. So how is it with a created being whose likenesses are many? It is the essence of ignorance to say,\'It is not permissible to know that which has a likeness and a correspondent, that is, The Spirit, while He makes binding spiritual knowledge of Him, Who has no like or correspondent.</item>
        <item> “So we invoke the protection of Allāh from the ignorance of the ignorant and from the wickedness of the evil doers. What I profess is that with Allāh there are secrets in which delineation is not possible and the concealment of which is not beneficial. They are not laid out in books for the spiritually blind and weak of discrimination and to conceal them is not fitting on account of their very obviousness and the clarity of their manifestation.</item>
        <item> “So pay not attention to them in spite of the multiplicity of their arguments. Be submissive to The Truth and be obedient to It in respect of those things with which they are concerned. Shun them in those things of which they have no knowledge. Allāh has commanded our Prophet Muhammad to follow after\'Ibrahim and the rest of the Prophets, peace and blessings upon them all. He is the most excellent, the one to whom none can attain and who says,\'I have become their partner in prophecy, awakening, guidance, the things befalling their lower selves, their bodies, minds and spirits.\' So imitate them in those things in which sharing is possible and those things which have been made their special property concern them and are for them {exclusively}.</item>
        <item> “In this way, whoever understands the Secret submits willingly to Allāh, together with the common believers, with those who are average and with the most advanced, and outranks them with respect to whatever is the special property of the favoured ones. If you are one of them, increase in your knowledge and in your religious practice as a faqir of Allāh and out of humility toward His Slaves and bend with compassion toward the common believers. Even though some of them are evil doers, except where Allāh commands you to deal harshly with them and even then make pious petition for them and plead on their behalf. I mention this in spite of your knowledge of the lack of certainty of what is less than this lest your self be disturbed and falsely claim that which does not belong to it.”</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc17">
        <item> At another gathering he said with reference to the Prophet\'s saying, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him, “Prayer {salāh} is the bond of union {silsilah} of the slave to his Lord,” “The sign of union is the pouring out of mercy with the manifestations of love. The manifestations of love are the removal of the veil and delight in our communion.”</item>
        <item> Another time he said, “I saw Abu Bakr as-Siddiq, may Allāh be content with him, in a dream and he asked me,\'Do you know what is the sign of love of the world leaving the heart?\' I replied,\'No.\' He said,\'Forsaking it upon finding it and finding relief upon losing it.\'”</item>
        <item> He said, “The private devotional exercises {awrād} of the faithful {siddiqun} are fasting, prayer, recitation of dhikr, recital of the Qur\'ān, guarding the openings of the body, turning the lower self away from appetitive desires, enjoining what is approved and prohibiting what is disapproved according to four principles: abstinence in respect to worldly things, trust in Allāh, acquiescence in the decrees of Allāh and patient endurance of the testing of Allāh. Sincere love is built upon four corners: faith, belief in the oneness of Allāh, right intention and high aspiration. If anyone does not have within himself four virtues, let him abandon hope of felicity: knowledge {\'ilm}, scrupulousness {wara\'}, awe before Allāh {haybah}, and humility towards the slaves of Allāh. The principles, corners and virtues are all necessary for the seeker.”</item>
        <item> He said, quoting his spiritual guide, “The worship {\'ibādah} of the trustworthy {siddiqun} consists of twenty things: eat, drink, clothe yourselves, travel, marry, settle down, do everything Allāh has commanded. Be not neglectful but serve Allāh. Associate neither any thing nor any one with Him. Be thankful to Him. Desist from injuring others and spend generously. This is one half. The other is performance of the prescribed duties, avoiding the unlawful and contentment with what Allāh decrees. Truly serving Allāh consists in reflecting upon the commands of Allāh and thoroughly studying the din. The most auspicious kind of service is asceticism with regards to the world, the chief principle of which is absolute trust in Allāh. This is the worship of the healthiest among the believers. If you are ill seek a remedy. Listen carefully to the learned ones, choose form among them the pious, the true guides, the trusting in Allāh.”</item>
        <item> He said, “I inquired of my spiritual guide concerning the spiritual practice {wird} of the most advanced muhaqqiqun and he replied,\'It is incumbent upon you to have done with passion {hawā} and to love the Friend of Allāh {wali}. The sure sign of love is the lover\'s being occupied with nothing except his Beloved.\'”</item>
        <item> He said, “If anyone has sufficiency with his possessions he is poor; if anyone has sufficiency with is high repute, he is despicable; if anyone has sufficiency with his kinsmen, he is contemptible; if anyone has sufficiency with his good works, he is bankrupt; if anyone has sufficiency with Allāh, he is truly rich.”</item>
        <item> He said, “The sign of commitment {tawfid} is lack of distress when distasteful things befall.”</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc18">
        <item> In addition to his oral lessons he also maintained a large correspondence with his  muridun especially addressing those who had remained behind in Tunis, and most especially Shaykh Abul Hasan as-Saqali and his old friend from the days of Jabal Zaghwān, Shaykh\'Abd as-Salāma al-Habibi, who remained in\'Irfiqiyyah maintaining a zāwiya for the local muridun in the village of Masruqin. These letters, like his discourses, have proved a rich mine for those who have sought to understand the Way of our Shaykh. His compassion and concern for his far-flung muridun was well-known, for he considered it the duty of the Shaykh as rabib {foster father} to know and directly aid his muridun.</item>
        <item> To Sidi\'Ali ibn Makhluf, a Sicillian murid living in Tunis, he wrote “So one of you seeks advice, one of you is silent and one is overcome in his anxiety. So, by Allāh, than Whom there is no other, if my sight were strong enough to help me do it, I would venture forth over every land and sea to my muridun until I should free them for what they cherish of our friendship, by the will and help of Allāh, for there is no power or might save with Allāh.” “Sit down by your\'door\' and you will get possession of everything that you may desire from the Possessor of Sovereignty {mālikul mulk}. Continue in the politeness pertaining to the Presence {hadrah} if you know it. If you do not know it, then understand from your\'mother\' something that will please you. For he who as access to the Presence has four homelands, all of which are centres of his consciousness; his spirit {ar-ruh}, his soul {an-nafs}, his heart {al-qalb}, and his mind {al-\'aql} which are brought into a state of tranquillity {tamān} by faith {imān}, unity {tawhid}, light {nur}, knowledge {\'ilm}, spiritual knowledge {ma\'rifah}, certain knowledge {\'ilm al-yaqin}, politeness {adab}, awe {rahbah}, brotherhood {\'ukhuwwah} and love {mahabbah}, making utterance with the tongue of clear meaning and saying according to each of the centres,\'Oh Allāh, I ask You that I may continue to look at You and listen to You, to be content with whatever comes to me from You. If you should cause me to turn back to Your creatures then I would ask You to be able to carry myself properly in drawing near to whoever draws near to You, and to turn away from whoever turns away from You. If You should cause me to turn back to Your Rights over me then I would ask You that I might carry myself according to the way of Your Prophet; and shut me not off from You by my own knowledge. If You should cause me to turn back to my own talents then I would ask You to enable me to do so by Your Permission through the concurrence of the utterance from You and the spiritual signs {\'ishārāt} that come from You. Make me one of those who accept that with that. Bring wisdom to our mouths, make our tongues to utter it, fill our hearts with it, and engage every part of our beings with it, within and without. Aid us by a Spirit from You that we do not harm our selves by our desires and that we do not follow our Shaytān. Appoint us to be of Your party,\'for the partisans of Allāh are the victorious.\'” {5:56}</item>
        <item> When he wrote to Sidi\'Ali bin Makhluf, who now rests in al-Zallāj Cemetery amongst the Tunisian awliyā al-\'arba\'un saying, “...if my sight were strong enough to help me do it, I would venture forth over every land and sea to my muridun,” it was not metaphorical. He was slowly losing his sight. This did not prevent him from continuing making Hajj almost every other year in the company of as many of the muridun as could accompany him nor did it prevent him from fighting in the front of the line of the battle of al-Mansurah when the Crusader forces under King Louis of France invaded Misr in 1250.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc19">
        <item> Many stories are told of that battle as well as\'the night of the tent\' that proceeded the battle. I direct the reader to the account of Shaykh\'Abd al-Halim Mahmud in Volume Two and especially his recounting of the ru\'ya of Shaykh Abul Hasan as related by Ibn as-Sabbagh for an appreciation of those events and what took place on that night. Suffice it to say that our Shaykh, and a great many of his muridun as well as his friends from amongst\'ulamā and awliyā upon hearing that the ummah was under attack immediately made their way to al-Mansurah to fight in the front lines seeking Victory or Paradise {an-Nasser aw al-Hannah} with full knowledge that “Paradise is in under the shadow of the sword.”</item>
        <item> On the day of the battle he mounted his best horse {he raised horses in that period and it was his most strong and beautiful mount} and had one of the muridun had him up his sword. When he had his sword to hand he asked for another, and with a sword in his right hand and a sword in his left hand he rode into battle. When asked later, given his deteriorating eyesight, how he could have ridden into battle and so honourably acquitted himself on the battle field he simply pointed to his heart saying. “If the eye of the heart sees clearly what need is there for my eyes?” Such was his vision.</item>
        <item> And do not say that those who are slain in the Way of Allāh are dead. Rather they are living but you do not perceive it. {2:154}  </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc20">
        <item> It is now ten years after our Shaykh entered al-\'Iskandariyah to dwell therein. He is sixty years of age and it is the month of Shawwāl in the six hundred and fifty sixth year of the Flight. The fasting month of Ramadān has just been completed and those who are leaving for Hajj from Misr are preparing their departure. In those days there were two principal routes for the pilgrimage to The Ancient House in Makkah the Blessed, the Northern and the Southern. The Northern route was the\'official\' caravan which carried the new covering {kiswah} for the Ka\'bah. It departed from al-Qāhirah on the 10th of Shawwāl, crossed the Eastern Desert, traversed the Sinai Desert and the turned south through the Hijāz to converge in Rabigh with the caravan coming from Dimishq {Damascus}. Approximately seven days after departing Rabigh the combined Hajj caravan entered the gates of Makkah. Total elapsed time was usually around 55 to 60 days. The advantages of the Northern Route were that it was shorter, officially organized and thus well provisioned and that the caravan had the protection of the soldiers of the Sultān to guard the Pilgrims against the usual problems of brigandage by the Badawi tribes of the Hijaz, who regularly fell upon the caravans and picked off the strays and laggards or those unfortunate enough to have their mounts die beneath them.</item>
        <item> Recall that this is the year in the Common Era {1258} when Hulugu, son of Jenghiz Khan, was at the gates of Baghdād. The whole eastern wing of Dār al-Islām is in a state of anarchy and destruction is rife. Refugees, lucky enough to escape the almost unbelievable ravages of the Mongol invasion, are flooding both Dimishq and al-Qāhirah. Many though it was the end of the world, as, in a certain way it was and, in another way, always is, at least for some.</item>
        <item> The Southern Route had no\'official\' or\'protected\' status. It was an ad hoc affair of small independent groups and followed the route that spices took coming into Misr. It was, however, because of the movement of spices, very well organized and, except for the crossing of the desert in Upper Egypt and the Red Sea crossing, a much easier journey and certainly more convivial. If one was coming from al-Iskandariyyah one went overland to Damanhur, then took ship first to al-Qāhirah where one stopped over for a few days then up the Nile by ship to\'Idfu in Upper Egypt, which was the terminus and trans-shipment centre from spices coming in from the Red Sea. The al-Qāhirah to\'Idfu leg usually took about two to three weeks and was a wonderful journey as the entire way was well provided with rest tops and numerous zawāyā providing the company of Friends night after night when the ships put into the banks of the Nile. All of this travel was made possible by the prevailing winds from the North which move the long-boomed lateen-rigged river ships upstream as the Nile, unlike most rivers, flows form the mountains of al-Habashah in the South to the Great Mid-Earth Sea In the North. In\'Idfu one crosses to the east bank and hires camels for crossing the desert in a series of fourteen stages to\'Aydhāb, of which Ibn Jubayr in his Rihlah remarked, “{It is} brackish of water and flaming of air,” and thence by ship again across the Red Sea to Jiddah which was a matter of five days to a week. From Jiddah, named for our great grandmother Sayyidatinā Hawwā\' {Eve}, the mercy of Allāh be upon her, and her resting place, may Allāh restore it and perfume it, it was two days by camel to Makkah al-Mukarramah. Though the distance is longer, the elapsed time {50-60 days} is roughly the same unless one chooses to prolong the journey and linger with Friends along the Way.</item>
        <item> Today the journey takes one and a half hours via 747 from Cairo airport to Jiddah. It too has its perils.</item>
        <item> It was our Shaykh\'s custom to take the Southern Route.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc21">
        <item> That year, after all preparation were complete, and just before departing from al-\'Iskandariyyah, the Shaykh requested that a pickaxe and a shovel be included in the baggage “In case one of us should die and burial should be necessary.” Sidi Mādi bin Sultān said that, “It had not been his custom in all of my travels with him.” When the group stopped in Damanhur there was a young boy, a student of Qur\'ān, who wished to go with them. His mother, for his father had died, said to the Shaykh, Yā Sidi, perhaps you will look after him, bi\'idhnillāh,” He replied, “InshaAllāh, we will look after him as far as Humaythirah.”</item>
        <item> From al-Qāhirah, presumably after visiting his grandfather Sayyidinā al-Husayn, may Allāh bless him, and grandmothers as-Sayyidah Zaynab and as-Sayyidah Nafisah, may Allāh bestow Mercy upon them as well as the many People of the House and Friends of Allāh in that great city, they began the long trip up the Nile. This journey, even in our day, is one of endless beauty. The fertile fields on either side unwind mile after mile in the most glorious greens. The fallahun, among the most productive farmers in the world, in ways unchanged since the world was young, till the fields in the company of their sleek, shining, black gamoosah. Animals, domestic and wild, abound and, always, a way beyond the nodding heads of the palms, the golden line of the desert where the virgin meets the sown shows itself against the distant hills. The sound is the sound of the river passing and the slow turning of the water wheels as the water is lifted to be spread upon the earth of more than fifty centuries of husbandry and farming. Our Shaykh, who himself farms, takes great interest in all of this even if, due to his failing eyesight, he depends on others for a view as to the passage on the great river. In the evenings he speaks in the soft golden glow of lamp lit Masājid large and small, touching the hearts, opening up the minds and raising up the spirits of all who hear, reminding them once and again of the eternal and present wonder of Allāh and the ever-living message delivered by His Unlettered Beloved, blessings of Allāh and eternal peace be upon him.</item>
        <item> After they reach\'Idfu and cross by ferry to the East bank they prepare for the trip across the desert of\'Aydhāb. Fourteen days to the Red Sea. The desert is not one of sand, except briefly near the Nile, but one of small stones and endless boulders and strange and often very beautifully formed mountains. Even in our time it is still mostly pristine and the air is startling in its diamond brilliance. It has a way of making everything seem sharper and somehow more in focus.</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc22">
        <item> Here let me switch to the account of Shaykh Sharaf ad-Din, son of Sidi Mādi bin Sultān, who heard it from his father as to the events that transpired. It was recorded by Ibn Sabbagh who also notes at the beginning of his final chapter in “The Pearl of Secrets and the Gem of the Devoted Ones” {Durat al-\'Asrār wa Tuhfat al-Abrār} the following: “One in whom I have confidence related to me that our Shaykh said,\'When I entered the land of Misr and established my dwelling there, I said,\'Yā Rabb, have You caused me to dwell in the land of the Copts {qibt} {hence the name used in the west for Misr “Eqibt” or Egypt} to be buried among them until my flesh becomes mingled with their flesh and my bones with their bones? A reply came to me,\'No\'Ali. You will be buried in a land which Allāh has never oppressed {daghata}.\'”</item>
        <item> To continue with the journey, “Just after entering the desert the young boy and our Shaykh both fell ill. The young boy died a day\'s journey before reaching the Well of Humaythirah. We wanted to bury him but he said,\'Carry him to Humaythirah.\' We halted and washed him and the Shaykh prayed over him and we buried him there. He was the first to be buried in that place.</item>
        <item> “That evening he assembled his companions and gave them final injunctions. He enjoined upon them the Orison of the Sea {Hizb al-Bahr} saying to them,\'Teach it to your children for in it is the Greatest Name of Allāh {al-ismul\'adham}. He talked in private with Sidi Abul\'Abbās al-Mursi, gave him orders and made him to be the especially favoured possessor of barakah. He said to the companions,\'When I am dead, look to Abul\'Abbās al-Mursi, for he is the Khalifah to succeed me. He will have an exalted station among you. He is one of the doors {abwāb} of Allāh, praise be to Him.\'</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc23">
        <item> “Between sunset and dusk he said to me,\'Yā Muhammad, fill for me a jar with water from this well.\' I said to him “Yā Sidi, its water is salty and bitter but the water we have is fresh.\' He said to me,\'Give me some of it for my intention is other than what you think.\' So we brought him a jug of water and he drank of it, rinsed his mouth and spat into the jar. Then he said to me,\'Put it back into the well.\' I put it back and the water of the well turned sweet and fresh and became abundant by the permission of Allāh.</item>
        <item> “He passed the night in orienting himself to Allāh {mutawajjih} and the recitation of dhikr. I heard him saying Allāhi, Allāhi.\' When the crack {falaq} opened {ie; when day broke}, he became still. Thinking him asleep we shook him and found him dead, may Allāh have mercy upon him. We called Sidi Abul\'Abbās al-Mursi and he washed him. We prayed over him and buried him in Humaythira\'. This place is in the desert of\'Aydhāb, by a valley upon the Sa\'id road. I have drunk of its water, I have visited his tomb and I have seen his barakah.”</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc24">
        <item> Sidi Mādi bin Sultān said in regard to his description, “He was of dark complexion, lean of body, tall of structure, thin bearded, long fingered, in appearance as those of the Hijāz. He was eloquent of tongue and suave of speech. He used to say, whenever in speaking he entered into profound discourse, “Is he not the choicest of men, who has a far better understanding of these secrets than we? Come to a man who Allāh has made to be a Sea of Lights.”</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="biographyc25">
        <item> Sidi Sharaf ad-Din went on to say, “After we buried him his companions were at variance as to turning back or proceeding. Sidi Abul Abbās al-Mursi said to them.\'Our Shaykh ordered me to perform the pilgrimage and promised me karāmāt.\' We proceeded and saw the way made easy for us and we experienced much barakah and returned in his company. He became thereafter the possessor of great renown and many karāmāt attended him.”</item>
        <item> “Abu\'Ishāq\'Ibrāhim Ibn\'Abd ar-Rafi\', the shaykh, faqih, khatib, mufti and qādi of the congregation in Tunis told me the following: “When Shaykh Abul Hasan set out to perform the hajj on the journey during which he passed away, he said to his muridun, “This year I shall perform the pilgrimage of substitution {hajjat an-niyābah}.\' He died before accomplishing the hajj. When his companions returned to Misr, they questioned the Mufti,\'Izz ad-Din Ibn\'Abd as-Salām and informed him of what he had said. He wept and said to them,\'The Shaykh, by Allāh, informed you that he would die. Do you not know that, by so saying, he instructed you that the Angel is the one who will perform the hajj in his place? The Hadith relates that the Prophet, blessings of Allāh and peace be upon him, said,\'If anyone leaves his home for the purpose of performing the hajj and dies before accomplishing the hajj, Allāh deputizes an angel to take his place in the performance of the hajj each year until the Day of Resurrection.\'”</item>
        <item> Such was his passing from our outward sight in this world and so it is we know that each year an Angel, deputized by Allāh, continues his hajj, fulfilling the rites of the circling of the Ancient House, the standing on Arafat, the stoning of Shaytān, performing the Sacrifice, drinking the waters of Zamzam and joining in the Farewell Circle. May we be honoured by the knowledge and company of that Angel, turning with him, standing by him. When he throws may we throw with him and may we our sacrifice be accepted with his. Let us, in his company, drink to repletion from the blessed spring of Zamzam from which Sayyidah Hajar and Sayyidinā\'Ismā\'il, peace be upon them, drank and give us to be connected, now and forever, with him and all the ummah in that Farewell Circle that has neither beginning or end.</item>
        <item> In al-\'Iskandariyyah, prior to departure for Hajj in the year of his death, our Shaykh was heard to say: “Once when I fell ill, I said, “Allāh, oh Allāh, when will the encounter take place?\' I was told,\'Yā\'Ali, when you reach Humaythira, then will come the encounter. I saw as if I were being buried at the base of a mountain before a well containing salty water which was becoming more abundant and sweet.” </item>
        <item> And how sweet it is.</item>
        <item> Surely the Friends of Allāh are those who shall neither fear nor shall they sorrow. {10:62}</item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="chapters">
        <item> The Birth of our Shaykh</item>
        <item> The Early Life our Shaykh</item>
        <item> Our Shaykh\'s search for the Qutb of the Age </item>
        <item> Finding the Qutb</item>
        <item> Departure to Shādhilah </item>
        <item> Receiving his nisbah ash-Shādhili and his orders </item>
        <item> Move to Tunis and meeting al-Khidr (May Allāh\'s mercy be upon him) </item>
        <item> The Envy of ibn al Bara </item>
        <item> The Envy of ibn al Bara continued </item>
        <item> The Envy of ibn al Bara continued (2) </item>
        <item> Our Shaykh\'s Return to Tunis and Meeting Abul \'Abbas al Mursi (May Allāh\'s mercy be upon him) </item>
        <item> The instruction to move to Al-Iskandariyyah (Alexandria, Egypt) </item>
        <item> The Journey to Egypt </item>
        <item> Our Shaykh\'s arrival in al-Iskandariyyah </item>
        <item> The Discourse of our Shaykh </item>
        <item> Our Shaykh\'s gatherings </item>
        <item> Our Shaykh\'s gatherings continued </item>
        <item> Letters to his Muridun </item>
        <item> The Jihad of our Shaykh </item>
        <item> 10 years after entering al-\'Iskandariyah and our Shaykh\'s final Hajj </item>
        <item> Departure for Hajj </item>
        <item> Shaykh Sharaf ad-Din\'s account of the last days of Our Shaykh </item>
        <item> The Passing of our Shaykh </item>
        <item> The Description of our Shaykh </item>
        <item> After our Shaykh\'s passing and closing remarks </item>
        <item> Taken from The School of the Shadhdhuliyyah, Volume 1, Orisons. Written by Shaykh \'Abdullah Nurudin Durkee. This work is available online at Greenmountainschool.org ISBN-10: 9770018309. Both Volume 1 and 2 are available in Hard and Soft cover printings. </item>
        <item> Please support the works of Shaykh Nurudin Durkee and the Green Mountain School who have sponsored this project and given permission for us to use their works free of charge for the sake of the Shadhili Way. </item>
        <item> Also available from Greenmountainschool.org are numerous Ahzab and Awrad of the Shadhdhuli Tariqa in inexpensive, small paperback form. These works are written in clear, original Arabic along with translation and transliteration. </item>
</string-array>
    <string-array name="extratitles">
        <item>Ismul-Jalaalah</item>
        
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="extrasubtitles">
        <item>The Grand Name</item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="supportlist">
        <item>The following organisations were fundamental to the success of this project. Click the organisation to go to their website.</item>

        <item>Shaykh Nooruddeen Durkee and The Green Mountain School - They provided us with the Biography of Imam Abul Hasan Ash-Shadhili and the Introduction to the Shadhili Way - Taken from Shaykh Nooruddeen\'s work \'The School of the Shadhdhuli Way - Volume 1 - Orisons\'</item>

        <item>Sacred Knowledge - They provided us with Awrad Texts and Audio recordings of Sayyid Shaykh Muhammad Al-Yaqoubi</item>

        <item>ShaykhFaisal.com/Islamic Forum Canada - They provided us with Awrad Texts and Audio recordings of Shaykh Faisal Hamid Abdur Razak</item>

        <item>Taqwa.sg - They provided us with Awrad Texts</item>

        <item>Please make dua for the brothers and sisters involved in these organisations and please support and promote their projects and works.</item>

    </string-array>


</resources>